Guide to the Capt. Edwin Fosha U.S. Civil War letters, 1862-1864 MS 664
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Capt. Edwin Fosha U.S. Civil War letters, 1862-1864
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Fosha, Edwin J., 1826-1864
MS 664
0.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
30 letters and envelopes written by Captain Edwin Fosha to his wife Rebecca Fosha and children in Illinois
Biographical Note
Edwin J. Fosha (1826-1864) joined the 91st Illinois Infantry at Camp Butler, Ill. on September 8, 1862 leaving his wife, Rebecca, and his 2 daughters (Frances and Eva) in Morris, Illinois. His military service would take him to Kentucky, Missouri, Louisiana, and Brownsville, Texas. He was captured with his regiment in Kentucky in December 1862. He was on duty as paroled prisoner in Benton Barracks, Missouri until July 1863. He traveled with his regiment south to New Orleans, LA., and eventually to Brownsville, Texas. He died in the Regimetal Hospital from acute dysentery in Brownsville, Texas on March 25, 1864.
Scope and Contents
30 letters and envelopes written by Captain Edwin Fosha to his wife Rebecca Fosha and children in Illinois.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated to the Woodson Research Center by Camille D. Simpson and Mary Axelrad, 2016.
General
Portions of this collection are available online at: https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/93747
Index Terms
Subjects
American Civil War (United States: 1861-1865); Soldiers--Correspondence
Document Types
letters (correspondence)
- Series I: Letters, 1862-1864
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Camp Butler Springfield, Illinois, 1862-09-07 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Springfield, Illinois, 1862-09-25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Springfield, Illinois, 1862-09-29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Camp Oakland, near Louisville, Kentucky, 1862-10-05 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Head Quarters Stockade No. 3, Elizabethtown, Kentucky, 1862-11-29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Elizabethtown, Kentucky, 1862-12-22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-01-29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-02-25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-03-27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-03-29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-04-22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-04-25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes additional letter dated 1863-04-25.
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-05-07 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes composition written by daughter Frances Fosha.
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-05-27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-06-01 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-06-03 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-06-07 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Benton Barracks, St. Louis, Missouri, 1863-07-03 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; New Orleans, Louisiana, 1863-08-20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; New Orleans, Louisiana, 1863-08-28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; New Orleans, Louisiana, 1863-09-17 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes second letter dated 1863-09-17.
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; New Orleans, Louisiana, 1863-10-04 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Brazos Del Santiago, Texas [mouth of the Rio Grande], 1863-11-03 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes second letter dated 1863-11-03.
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Brownsville, Texas, 1863-12-10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Brownsville, Texas, 1864-01-22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Brownsville, Texas, 1864-01-22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Brownsville, Texas, 1864-01-26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Brownsville, Texas, 1864-01-28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Brownsville, Texas, 1864-02-15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Edwin Fosha to Rebecca Fosha; Brownsville, Texas, 1864-02-18 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Capt. B. Newman to Mrs. E. J. Fosha, 1864-03-25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Envelopes, circa 1862-1864
  - Two envelopes, circa 1862-1864 (Box 1, Folder 3)